<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My External Brain</title><link>https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/</link><description>Recent content on My External Brain</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fingerprinting</title><link>https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/topics/privacy/fingerprinting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/topics/privacy/fingerprinting/</guid><description>Over the last years we have seen many aggressive efforts from different companies (Apple, Mozilla) to limit the amount of tracking that can be done through browsers1. Because of these efforts advertisers had to find different ways to track users across the web.
The approach of fingerprinting is using different difficult to hide data-points from a user to identify him/her again on a next visit. In contrast to tracking an ip-address or your browsing mode, using this method of tracking, you give &amp;ldquo;innocent-looking but largely unchanging technical information about your computer, such as the resolution of your screen, your operating system or the fonts you have installed&amp;quot;2.</description></item><item><title>HTTPS</title><link>https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/topics/computer-science/security/https/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/topics/computer-science/security/https/</guid><description>This article is mostly my summary of the Wikipedia page on HTTPS1 and TLS2.
HTTPS is the secure version of HTTP, however I was interested in how the security of HTTPS is made up. HTTS is also named HTTP over TLS (previously HTTP over SSL). Here TLS is providing the layer of security that is supposed to protect our privacy and the integrity of the data we load and send.</description></item><item><title>TLS</title><link>https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/topics/computer-science/security/tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.nickbelzer.me/topics/computer-science/security/tls/</guid><description> The illustrated TLS 1.3 connection</description></item></channel></rss>